A Guide to the Harry Atwood Film Collection, 1949-1995.
Harry Atwood Film Collection
1949-1995
Atwood, Harry
25 ft.
Dolph Briscoe Center for American History, The University of Texas at Austin
Short documentary films which yield sensory impressions of the visions of the creator.
Biographical Note
Harry Atwood is a graduate of the University of Arizona from which he holds a Bachelors and a Masters in Music and a film graduate from the University of Southern California in Los Angeles. He has made over sixty films, but only calls thirty his own creations or impressions. His focus has shifted from people to nature, because he says it has so much more to say. His films have won blue ribbons from the American Film Festival and Golden Eagle Awards for international non-theatrical events.
Scope and Contents
Short films created by award-winning documentary filmmaker Harry Atwood combine music and sounds of nature with visual images to express his impressions of specific places or events. Films include: The Great Unfenced (1963), about a cattle station in the outback of western Australia; Paths in the Wilderness (1976), concerning the missions of Padre Kino in southern Arizona and northern Mexico; and High on the Wild (1987), impressions of the Alaska wilderness and its dramatic landscape. The collection also contains Atwood's notes relating to each film and on-location photographs and sound recordings.
Arrangement
The materials are listed by title of film or event filmed.
The dates given for the films refer to the date of release; filming itself usually occurred one year prior to the date listed.
Access Restriction
Restricted access to portions of this collection; all copyright restrictions apply. Portions of this collection are stored remotely. Advance notice is required for retrrieval. Contact repository for retrieval.
Related Material
The original master videotape versions of Harry Atwood's films are located in the Consolidated Film Industries laboratory in Los Angeles, California.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Atwood, Harry W., 1927- --Archives.
Subjects
Alcoholism.; Architecture--Peru.; Architecture--Mexico.; Carnival--Brazil.; Dancing--Africa.; Graphic arts--United States.; Motion picture music--United States.; Muczynski, Robert, 1929-, composer.; Music--Africa.; Music--Brazil.; Painting--United States.; Ranch life--Arizona.; Ranch life--Australia.; Storms--Hawaii.; Volcanoes--Hawaii.; Volcanoes--Sicily (Italy)
Detailed Description
- UNRESTRICTED MATERIALS, I. (Box 3W117)
  - VIDEOS OF FILMS (Box 3W117)
  - Harry Atwood Film Collection: (Box 3W117)
    - SEVENTEEN FILMS ON DIGITAL VIDEO DISCS (DVD): (Box 3W117)
      - Volume 1: (Box 3W117)
        - Journey Through Eden (Box 3W117)
        - The Back of Beyond (Box 3W117)
        - Adagio (Box 3W117)
        - Remembrance (Box 3W117)
      - Volume 2: (Box 3W117)
        - Paths in the Wilderness (Box 3W117)
        - Fever (Box 3W117)
        - Fantasmas (Box 3W117)
        - Fire on the Sea (Box 3W117)
      - Volume 3: (Box 3W117)
        - The Great Unfenced (Box 3W117)
        - Yankee Painter (Box 3W117)
        - Cajititlan (Box 3W117)
        - Bellota (Box 3W117)
      - Volume 4: (Box 3W117)
        - Tiger by the Tail (Box 3W117)
        - Genesis (Box 3W117)
        - Mokum (Box 3W117)
        - Winter Light (Box 3W117)
        - Sagaland (Box 3W117)
    - 1/2 inch VHS videocassettes: (Box 3Y342)
      - *Adagio, impressions of Venice in winter, 1984 [from first master] (VHS from 2nd Master is best; see pg. 2). (Box 3Y342)
      - American Realists, a survey of realism in American painting from the 18th century into the 20th century, 1965 (Box 3Y342)
      - Back of Beyond, life in the Hebridean Islands off the west coast of Scotland, 1983 (Box 3Y342)
      - Bellota, a month long roundup on a large cattle ranch in southern Arizona, 1969 (Box 3Y342)
      - Cajititlan, life in a Mestizo village in Jalisco, Mexico, 1965 (Box 3Y342)
      - Charles Burchfield, 1966 (Box 3Y342)
      - The Clowns Never Laugh, 1967 (Box 3Y342)
      - Fantasmas, remains of the Inca Empire in an awesome setting, the Andes of Peru, 1978 (Box 3Y342)
      - **Fever, Carnival in Bahia, Brazil, 1977 (best VHS is from extra 3/4″; see pg. 3) (Box 3Y342)
      - Fire on the Sea, the people (and volcanoes) of the islands of Sicily and Stromboli, 1980 (Box 3Y342)
      - Genesis, forces of nature filmed on the islands of Maui and Hawaii: sea, tropical storm and eruption of the volcano, Kilauea, 1985 (Box 3Y342)
      - The Great Unfenced, a cattle station on the Great Western Desert of Australia, 1963 (Box 3Y342)
      - High on the Wild, some impressions of Alaska, sea life, glaciers, etc., 1987 (Box 3Y343)
      - John Marin, the great oils and watercolors of the brilliant American painter, 1968 (Box 3Y343)
      - Journey Through Eden, tribal music and dance, landscape and animals of East Africa, 1975 (Box 3Y343)
      - Mokum, Amsterdam in autumn, impressions of a beautiful, unique and lively city, 1990 (Box 3Y343)
      - Paths in the Wilderness, Padre Kino and his missions in Sonora, Mexico, and southern Arizona, 1976 (Box 3Y343)
      - Remembrance, filmed in Copenhagen, Denmark, 1992 (Box 3Y343)
      - Sagaland, some impressions of Iceland, Europe's greatest waterfalls, glacier and fantastic landscapes, 1989 (Box 3Y343)
      - Tiger by the Tail, a 72-year-old alcoholic's road to recovery, 1970 (Box 3Y343)
      - Winter Light, some impressions of Norway from Oslo to Bergen, 1991 (Box 3Y343)
      - Yankee Painter, the drawings, watercolors and oils of Winslow Homer, 1964 (Box 3Y343)
      - Summer Odyssey, filmed in Europe and Russia, 1972 (Box 2.325/J3 (05301740))
      - Bridge to the East, filmed in the Orient, 1973 (Box 2.325/J3 (05301740))
      - *Adagio, 1984, [Best VHS copy from better second master] (Box 95-171/1 (04750024))
      - Charles Burchfield 1966/ Masterpiece of Spanish Painting, 1961 (Box 95-171/1 (04750024))
      - Terra Sancta Revisited, filmed in Israel, 1968 [revised version] (Box 95-171/1 (04750024))
      - Journey Thru Eden/ **Fever, filmed in East Africa and Brazil [extra VHS copy; best VHS copy of Fever] (Box 3W117)
      - Television interviews of Harry Atwood, January 1969, March 1981, February 1983 (Box 3W117)
    - 3/4 inch videocassette sub-masters:, (can be used for making VHS dubs for general use. Best quality VHS or 3/4″ cassette dubs should be made from one inch Sub-Masters or one inch Masters). (Box 3Y341)
      - *Adagio, 1984 [from first master] (3/4″ from 2nd Master is best; see pg. 4) (Box 3Y341)
      - Back of Beyond, 1983 (Box 3Y341)
      - Bellota, 1969 (Box 3Y341)
      - Cajititlan, 1965 (Box 3Y341)
      - Fantasmas, 1978 (Box 3Y341)
      - **Fever, 1977 (Extra 3/4 inch cassette is best; see below). (Box 3Y341)
      - Fire on the Sea, 1980 (Box 3Y341)
      - Genesis, 1985 (Box 3Y341)
      - The Great Unfenced, 1963 (Box 3Y341)
      - High on the Wild, 1987 (Box 3Y341)
      - Journey Through Eden, 1975 (Box 3Y341)
      - Mokum, 1990 (Box 3Y341)
      - Paths in the Wilderness, 1976 (Box 3Y341)
      - Remembrance, 1993 (Box 3Y341)
      - Sagaland, 1989 (Box 3Y341)
      - Tiger by the Tail, 1970 (Box 3Y341)
      - Winter Light, 1991 (Box 3Y341)
      - Journey Through Eden, Africa, 1975/ **Fever, Brazil, 1977 [extra 3/4 inch cassette, best 3/4 inch of Fever] (Box 3W117)
      - Summer Odyssey, Europe/Russia, 1972 (Box 2.325/J3 (05301740))
      - Bridge to the East, Asia, 1973 (Box 2.325/J3 (05301740))
      - *Adagio, 1984 [best 3/4 inch cassette from better second master] (Box 95-171/1 (04750024))
      - Charles Burchfield, 1966/ Masterpiece of Spanish Painting, 1961 (Box 95-171/1 (04750024))
      - Terra Sancta Revisited [revised version of a film photographed in Israel in 1966] (Box 95-171/1 (04750024))
      - American Painter series: (Box 3Y189.4)
        - American Realists, parts I and II, 1965 (Box 3Y189.4)
        - Charles Burchfield, 1966 (Box 3Y189.4)
        - The Clowns Never Laugh, 1967 (Box 3Y189.4)
        - John Marin, 1968 (Box 3Y189.4)
        - Yankee Painter, 1964 (Box 3Y189.4)
  - PAPERS, ETC. (Box 96-054/1 (04913901))
  - Journals, 1960-1994 [Atwood's thoughts on filming, editing and sound, his films] (Box 96-054/1 (04913901))
  - Filming abroad correspondence, 1960-1992 [letters from abroad concerning filming experiences] (Box 96-054/1 (04913901))
  - Addenda to journal and filming abroad correspondence: (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
    - Scrapbooks: (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
      - Early life, early films, drawings (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
      - Extra correspondence, notes, clippings, mementos concerning films (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
      - Photostats of location photos (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
      - Film reviews (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
      - Narrative scripts (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
      - Ownership, sales and distribution records of films from 1960s into the 1970s (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
      - Additional location photos (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
      - ACT Award Night, June 5, 1976 (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
      - Lists: (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
        - Labs holding video masters (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
        - Labs holding film originals (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
        - Former distributors of films (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
        - Music and recordings used in some of the films (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
        - Film awards (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
        - Quotes concerning films (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
  - Location materials [dates refer to year of filming]: (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
    - Editing and music notes: (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
      - Remembrance, Copenhagen, 1992 (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
    - Camera notes: (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
      - A Portrait of Europe, 1959 (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
      - The Aged Land, Greece, 1960 (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
      - A Portrait of Mexico, 1961 (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
      - The Great Unfenced, Australia, 1962 (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
      - Cajititlan, Mexico, 1964 (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
      - Terra Sancta, Israel, 1966 (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
      - Summer Odyssey, Europe, Russia, 1971 (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
      - Bridge to the East, South Pacific, Orient, 1972 (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
      - Journey Through Eden, East Africa, 1973 (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
      - Fever, Rio and Bahia Brazil, 1976 (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
      - Fantasmas, Peru, 1977 (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
      - Fire on the Sea, Sicily, Stromboli, 1978 (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
      - The Back of Beyond, Scotland, 1982 (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
      - Adagio, Venice, Italy, 1983 (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
      - Genesis, Hawaii, 1985 (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
      - High on the Wild, Alaska, 1986 (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
      - Sagaland, Iceland, 1988 (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
      - Mokum, Amsterdam, 1989 (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
      - Winter Light, Norway, 1991 (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
      - Remembrance, Copenhagen, 1992 (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
    - Lago Cajititlan, photocopy of background material on village of Cajititlan, Mexico, for film script, ca. 1960 (Box 96-308/1 (04991847))
  - Library of Congress card catalog cards describing 20 of Harry Atwood's films (Box 3W117)
  - The Atwood DVD Film Collection, brochures (Box 3W117)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS: (Box 96-308/2 (04991698))
    - Photographic slides, color: (Box 96-308/2 (04991698))
      - Mexico, filming with Connie Helmericks, summer, 1957 (Box 96-308/2 (04991698))
    - Photographic prints, color: (Box 96-308/2 (04991698))
      - The Hebrides, Scotland, photographs by N. Shelton and Steve Burns, 1982 (Box 96-308/2 (04991698))
      - Greece, 1960 (Box 96-308/2 (0491698))
      - Australia, 1962 (Box 96-308/2 (04991698))
      - Early photographs, 1950s (Box 96-308/2 (04991698))
    - Photographs from Atwood's twenty filming trips: (Box 3S49.3)
      - 249 35mm slides (Box 3S49.3)
      - 1,104 35mm negatives (Box 3S49.3)
      - 225 color and black white photographic prints (Box 3S49.3)
    - Newspaper photographs (Box 3S49.3)
  - Brochures for all films (Box 3S49.3)
  - Atwood art film catalog (Box 3S49.3)
  - Act Award night, 1976 [celluloid strip in cardboard cylinder] (Box 3S49.3)
  - Brochures: (Box 95-273/2 (04913923))
    - A Portrait of Mexico (Box 95-273/2 (04913923))
    - De Grazia (Box 95-273/2 (04913923))
    - The Last Wagon (Box 95-273/2 (04913923))
    - Terra Sancta (Box 95-273/2 (04913923))
  - SOUND RECORDINGS [1/4 inch phonotapes and audiocassettes]: (Box 2.325/R51)
    - Location recordings for films [phonotape]: (Box 2.325/R51)
      - Fever, Brazil, 1976, reels I and II (Box 2.325/R51)
      - Copenhagen, 1992 (Box 2.325/R51)
      - Journey Through Eden, East Africa, 1973: (Box 2.325/R51)
        - Tapes I-III (Box 2.325/R51)
        - Tapes IV-VI (Box 2.325/R51)
        - Tapes VII-IX (Box 2.325/R51)
        - Tapes X-XI (Box 2.325/R51)
        - Reels I and II (Box 2.325/R51)
      - Fire on the Sea, Sicily and Egypt, October through November, 1978 (Box 2.325/R51)
      - Sicily and Stromboli, 1978, reels I and II (Box 2.325/R51)
      - Venice, Italy, 1983 (Box 2.325/R51)
      - Amsterdam, 1989 (Box 2.325/R51)
      - Israel, 1966, reels I and II (Box 2.325/R51)
      - Peru, 1977 (Box 2.325/R51)
      - Scotland, 1982, reels I and II (Box 2.325/R51)
      - Bellota Ranch, Arizona, 1967 (Box 2.325/R51)
      - Cajititlan, Mexico, 1964 (Box 2.325/R51)
      - South Pacific, Orient, 1972, reels I and II (Box 2.325/R51)
      - Europe, Russia, 1971, reels I, II and III (Box 2.325/R51)
    - Music scores, by Robert Muczynski: (Box 2.325/R51)
      - The Great Unfenced, 1963 (Box 2.325/R51)
      - Yankee Painter, 1964 (Box 2.325/R51)
      - American Realists, 1965 (Box 2.325/R51)
      - Charles Burchfield, 1966 (Box 2.325/R51)
      - The Clowns Never Laugh, 1967 (Box 2.325/R51)
      - Terra Sancta, 1968 (Box 2.325/R51)
      - Bellota, 1969 (Box 2.325/R51)
      - Journey Through Eden, 1975 (Box 2.325/R51)
      - Cajititlan, 1965 (Box 95-273/2 (04913923))
    - Atwood's master piano recital broadcast, 1954 (Box 95-273/2 (04913923))
    - Some interviews, Tiger by the Tail, 1970, I-V (Box 2.325/R51)
    - Some sacred music, Paths in the Wilderness, 1976, I-III (Box 2.325/R51)
    - Music for Three Films, Robert Muczynski [phonodisk] (Box 2.325/R51)
    - Music of Robert Muczynski: Five Film Scores [compact disc] (Box 2.325/R51)
    - Music of Robert Muczynski: Two Orchestral Works, Two Film Scores [compact disc] (Box 2.325/R51)
    - AUDIOCASSETTES: (Box 3w118d)
      - Journal, 1962-1992 [Atwood reads from his journal]: (Box 3w118d)
        - Introduction (Box 3w118d)
        - Great Unfenced and Yankee Painter/ Cajititlan and Terra Sancta (Box 3w118d)
        - Bellota, Tiger By The Tail, Summer Odyssey/ Bridge to the East, Journey Thru Eden [beginning] (Box 3w118d)
        - Journey Thru Eden [conclusion], Fever [beginning]/ Paths in the Wilderness, Fantasmas (Box 3w118d)
        - Fire on the Sea, Back of Beyond/ Adagio, Genesis, High on the Wild (Box 3w118d)
        - Sagaland, Mokum/ Winter Light, Remembrance (Box 3w118d)
        - Filming abroad [Atwood reads from letters]: (Box 3w118d)
          - Australia, June 19, July 8, 23, 30, August 14, 1962 (Box 3w118d)
          - Greece, June-July 1960, Mexico, July-August 1964 [beginning] (Box 3w118d)
          - Mexico, July-August 1964 [conclusion], Israel, July-August 1966 (Box 3w118d)
          - Russia/Europe, June-July 1971 (Box 3w118d)
          - The Orient/South Pacific, July-August 1972 (Box 3w118d)
          - East Africa, July-August 1973 (Box 3w118d)
          - Brazil, March-April 1976 (Box 3w118d)
          - Letter from Peru, March 1976, end of Brazil trip, Sicily, October-November 1978 (Box 3w118d)
          - Sicily/Egypt November 1978, Scotland, June-July 1982 (Box 3w118d)
      - Location recordings on audiocassette [extra and more complete copies]: (Box 3w118d)
        - Mexico ( Cajititlan), 1964 (Box 3w118d)
        - Israel [excerpts], 1966 (Box 3w118d)
        - East Africa, 1973 (Box 3w118d)
        - Brazil, February and March 1976 (Box 3w118d)
        - Sicily and Egypt [excerpts], October-November 1978 (Box 3w118d)
        - Scotland, 1982 (Box 3w118d)
        - Venice, December 1983 (Box 3w118d)
        - Amsterdam, October 1989 (Box 3w118d)
      - Audio cassette, music from early films, 1960-1972 (Box 95-273/2 (04913923))
- RESTRICTED MATERIALS, II.; FOR PRESERVATION ONLY, not for Public Use: (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
  - SEVENTEEN FILMS ON DIGITAL VIDEO DISCS (DVD): (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
    - Sub-masters: (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
      - 3/4 in. cassettes, NTSC digital betacam sub-masters (for DVD): (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
      - Sub-master #1: (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - Journey Through Eden (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - The Back of Beyond (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - Adagio (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - Remembrance (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
      - Sub-master #2: (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - Paths in the Wilderness (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - Fever (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - Fantasmas (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - Fire on the Sea (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
      - Sub-master #3: (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - The Great Unfenced (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - Yankee Painter (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - Cajititlan (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - Bellota (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
      - Sub-master #4: (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - Tiger by the Tail (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - Genesis (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - Mokum (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - Winter Light (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - Sagaland (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
    - DVDs: (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
      - Volume 1: (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - Journey Through Eden (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - The Back of Beyond (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - Adagio (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - Remembrance (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
      - Volume 2: (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - Paths in the Wilderness (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - Fever (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - Fantasmas (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - Fire on the Sea (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
      - Volume 3: (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - The Great Unfenced (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - Yankee Painter (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - Cajititlan (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - Bellota (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
      - Volume 4: (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - Tiger by the Tail (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - Genesis (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - Mokum (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - Winter Light (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
        - Sagaland, FOR PRESERVATION ONLY, not for Public Use: (use only in case of broadcast or for making best quality 3/4 inch and 1/2 inch videocassette dubs) (These are the best quality other than the ones still retained in studios in California.). (Most important to the Collection). (Box 2000-97/1 (07993190))
    - One inch video sub-masters: (Box 94-310/1 (05298770))
      - The Great Unfenced (Box 94-310/1 (05298770))
      - Yankee Painter (Box 94-310/1 (05298770))
      - American Realist (Box 94-310/1 (05298770))
      - Cajititlan [condensed 29 minute version] (Box 94-310/1 (05298770))
      - Charles Burchfield and The Clowns Never Laugh (Box 94-310/1 (05298770))
      - John Marin (Box 94-310/1 (05298770))
      - Bellota (Box 94-310/1 (05298770))
      - Tiger by the Tail, FOR PRESERVATION ONLY, not for Public Use: (Box 94-310/1 (05298770))
      - Journey Through Eden (Box 94-310/2 (05298759))
      - Paths in the Wilderness (Box 94-310/2 (05298759))
      - Fever (Box 94-310/2 (05298759))
      - Fantasmas (Box 94-310/2 (05298759))
      - Fire on the Sea (Box 94-310/2 (05298759))
      - The Back of Beyond (Box 94-310/2 (05298759))
      - Adagio [from first master] (Box 94-310/2 (05298759))
      - Genesis, FOR PRESERVATION ONLY, not for Public Use: (Box 94-310/2 (05298759))
      - High on the Wild (Box 94-310/3 (05299015))
      - Sagaland (Box 94-310/3 (05299015))
      - Mokum (Box 94-310/3 (05299015))
      - Winter Light (Box 94-310/3 (05299015))
      - Remembrance, FOR PRESERVATION ONLY, not for Public Use: (Box 94-310/3 (05299015))
      - Adagio, 1984 [copied from better second master] (Box 95-304/1 (04913898))
      - Terra Sancta Revisited, FOR PRESERVATION ONLY, not for Public Use: (Box 95-304/1 (04913898))
      - Bridge to the East, FOR PRESERVATION ONLY, not for Public Use: (Box 97-037/3 (6196380))
      - Cajititlan [original 41 minute version], FOR PRESERVATION ONLY, not for Public Use: (Box 97-037/4 (6196379))
      - Summer Odyssey, FOR PRESERVATION ONLY, not for Public Use: (Box 97-037/9 (6195059))
  - 16mm sound film prints: (Box 94-082/1 (03120585))
    - Charles Burchfield, print #2, 1966 (Box 94-082/1 (03120585))
    - Genesis, print #3 (7399), 1985 (Box 94-082/1 (03120585))
    - Sagaland, 3rd positive print, 1989 (Box 94-082/1 (03120585))
    - Fantasmas, print #3, 1978 (Box 94-082/1 (03120585))
    - Winter Light, 1st positive trial, 1991 (Box 94-082/1 (03120585))
    - High on the Wild, print #4, 1987 (Box 94-082/1 (03120585))
    - Remembrance, print #3, 1993 (Box 94-082/1 (03120585))
    - American Realists, part 1, XVIII-XIX Centuries, print #4, 1965 (Box 94-082/1 (03120585))
    - American Realists, part 2, XX Centuries, extra print #1, 1965 (Box 94-082/1 (03120585))
    - Paths in the Wilderness, print #4, 1976, FOR PRESERVATION ONLY, not for Public Use: (Box 94-082/1 (03120585))
    - Yankee Painter: The Work of Winslow Homer, extra print, 1964 (Box 94-082/2 (03120461))
    - The Great Unfenced, print #2 (revised), 1963 (Box 94-082/2 (03120461))
    - Tiger by the Tail, extra print, 1970 (Box 94-082/2 (03120461))
    - Fever, print #4, 1977 (Box 94-082/2 (03120461))
    - Mokum: Amsterdam in Autumn, print #2, 1990 (Box 94-082/2 (03120461))
    - Bellota: A Story of Roundup, extra print, 1969 (Box 94-082/2 (03120461))
    - Adagio: Venice in Winter, print #1, 1984 (Box 94-082/2 (03120461))
    - Journey Through Eden, print #2, 1975, FOR PRESERVATION ONLY, not for Public Use: (Box 94-082/2 (03120461))
    - Fire on the Sea, print #2, 1980, FOR PRESERVATION ONLY, not for Public Use: (Box 94-082/3 (03120596))
    - Terra Sancta Revisited, 16mm color sound print of original 1968 version, FOR PRESERVATION ONLY, not for Public Use: (Box 95-304/1 (04913898))
    - The Clowns Never Laugh [print number 1, 1967] (Box 94-310/4 (05298748))
    - John Marin [print number 1, 1968] (Box 94-310/4 (05298748))
    - A Masterpiece of Spanish Printing [print number 10, 1961] (Box 94-310/4 (05298748))
    - Bridge of the East [print number 2, 1973] (Box 94-310/4 (05298748))
    - Summer Odyssey [print number 4, 1972], FOR PRESERVATION ONLY, not for Public Use: (Box 94-310/4 (05298748))
    - Cajititlan, 16mm color, full length 41 minute version, 1965, FOR PRESERVATION ONLY, not for Public Use: (Box 97-261/1 (06195060))
    - A Portrait of Mexico, 1961-1962 (Box 95-273/1 (04913912))
    - De Grazia, 1967 (Box 95-273/1 (04913912))
    - The Last Wagon, 1970 (Box 95-273/1 (04913912))
    - The Aged Land, 1961 (Box 95-273/1 (04913912))
    - Christmas of the Southwest, revised, 1955, b and w, sound (Box 95-273/1 (04913912))
    - University of Symphony Orchestra, 1957 (Box 95-273/1 (04913912))
    - The Kress Collection, revised, 1957, color, sound (Box 95-273/1 (04913912))
    - A Portrait of Europe, 1959, Kodachrome composite, FOR PRESERVATION ONLY, not for Public Use: (Box 95-273/1 (04913912))
  - EARLY FILMS: VARIOUS FORMATS (Box 94-124/2 (05228844))
  - VIDEO VHS AND 3/4 INCH:: (Box 94-124/2 (05228844))